hello and welcome to the 14th tutorial
on how to program a g-script 2. so let's
double click our NPC and as you can see
I added a bunch new lines of code in the
uncreated function this is pretty much
the gscript 2 counterpart of
what we saw in the
way that the NPCs created in g-script
one
cycle look
and just script one this is what it
would look like
now in g-script 2. this is what it would
look like
these comments are here so you can see
what they would look like before I can
get rid of them if I wanted to this is
required to tell it that we're going to
make it look like a player
make the NPCs look like a player this is
the hand image
this these five lines are the colors
that the NPC has like shoes and sleeves
the first one
is the skin the second one is the coat
the third is the
sleeves
the fourth is the shoes and the fifth is
the belt it says zero one two three four
five I mean one two three four even
though I'm saying one two three four
five but these are arrays and we're not
gonna get into them right now
but just know
that yeah these make the colors of the
NPC
this is The Shield image that the NPC
has
and this is required so for the image of
the shield to appear you're not ever
going to use this outside of making the
shield appear unless you're going for
the default growl systems but we're not
gonna do that
and this is the NPC's Direction that's
the way it's facing
currently it's facing two
this makes the MPC face downwards
if we made it to zero it would face
upwards who made it one it would face
left and three would make its face to
right
now let's add a new line of code here
make it
this
changes the animation of the NPC or it's
ghani
we can actually take out this because
it's not like server side or anything
but we'll just add that
this first parameter is the name of the
ghani which is walk which is default the
second one isn't very important and
you can usually Skip and I'm not sure
what it really does but nothing has ever
changed when I've changed it
adding null is the same as adding
nothing but we're just gonna add note to
show to show that there's nothing there
if you want to change the players gone
and we put set
Ani
walk
no
this changes the players animation
so anyway we don't need this here
let's just save it
and see what happens
well you kind of know all we've changed
is the animation oh we've forgot we
forgot to take out the second NPC
there
it's running downwards at the same time
while running to the right
well that concludes this tutorial we
learned about the gscript 2 version of
creating the actual NPC and making it
look like a player
and we learned how to change the
animation next tutorial I'm going to
show a bit we're going to continue on
our little moving NPC so bye